<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>io.github.BryamContreras.BExplorer</id>
  <metadata_license>MIT</metadata_license>
  <project_license>MIT</project_license>
  <name>BExplorer</name>
  <summary>Native Rust file explorer</summary>
  <developer id="io.github.bexplorer-project">
    <name>BExplorer Project</name>
  </developer>
  <description>
    <p>
      BExplorer is a native Rust desktop file explorer focused on fast file
      management, split-pane workflows, archive handling, previews, and a
      compact interface.
    </p>
  </description>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">bexplorer.desktop</launchable>
  <provides>
    <binary>bexplorer</binary>
  </provides>
  <categories>
    <category>Utility</category>
    <category>FileManager</category>
  </categories>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />
  <releases>
    <release version="1.0.3" date="2026-07-24">
      <description>
        <p>Compact-image, rename, scrolling, and release-packaging update.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed Control-key scrolling and filename-extension editing in every file view.</li>
          <li>Added dedicated compact thumbnails and native icons for small views and the sidebar.</li>
          <li>Added automated Windows Setup, Debian, and RPM package generation.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.2" date="2026-07-15">
      <description>
        <p>Linux desktop integration and native properties update.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Added compact native Properties and functional Open with workflows on Linux.</li>
          <li>Improved symbolic links, keyboard navigation, and address-bar focus handling.</li>
          <li>Added XDG application chooser portal and complementary KIO/KIOFuse discovery.</li>
          <li>Improved Debian dependencies, themed icons, and default file-manager invocation.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.1" date="2026-07-14">
      <description>
        <p>Maintenance release with Windows and Linux integration refinements.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed the transient Windows frame shown during the first external file drag.</li>
          <li>Improved printer artwork and Windows release packaging.</li>
          <li>Refined Linux storage, formatting, blur, drag-and-drop, and shutdown behavior.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.0" date="2026-07-13">
      <description>
        <p>First stable BExplorer release for Windows and Linux.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Tabbed and split-pane file management with session restore.</li>
          <li>Reliable queued transfers, conflict handling, archives, search, and previews.</li>
          <li>Native Windows integration and desktop-neutral Linux integration.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
